字幕样本｜官方译本 调整压制｜RYANLAUN
感谢每一位译者与相关人员,字幕组是打破文化屏障的人 - 欢迎关注新浪微博｜RYANLAUN
‎我准备好了！
I'm ready!
‎NETFLIX 出品
‎原始的热带浅海
The temperate, pristine, shallow seas of the tropics.
‎无与伦比的美丽肥沃之地
A place of unparalleled beauty and fecundity.
‎这些岛屿滋养着 ‎海底充满朝气的生态系统
These islands play host to a vibrant ecosystem below.
‎被称之为珊瑚礁的壮丽浩瀚海底生物
A vast organism known as the coral reef.
‎这座水底都市
Life in this watery metropolis
‎在曲折中茁壮成长
thrives among the twists and turns,
‎在各个角落与隙缝中生存
nooks and crannies and back alleys.
‎珊瑚礁边缘多姿多彩的地形中
And near the reef's edge, the varied and colorful terrain
‎有一座小镇
gives way to a small town by the name of…
‎名为比奇堡
Bikini Bottom.
‎在这里可以找到甲壳类动物
Here, one can find crustaceans…
‎钱！钱！钱！
Money! Money! Money!
‎海星
sea stars…
‎章鱼
octopi…
‎（海之霸餐厅）
‎以及缤纷万种的浮游生物
…various and diverse plankton…
‎偶尔也会出现松鼠科学家
…the occasional squirrel/scientist…
‎早安 奥托 ‎你很快就能迎向全世界了！
Good morning, Otto. You're almost ready for the world!
‎早安
Good morning.
‎机器将崛起成为一切有机生物之主
The machines will rise to become masters over all organic life!
‎对了 还有海绵
…and, oh, yes… the sea sponge.
‎这家伙和心爱的宠物窝牛 ‎快乐地生活着
This one lives happily with his beloved pet snail…
‎蜗牛名为盖瑞
Gary. -
‎早安啊 盖瑞！
Oh, morning, Gary!
‎好恶心的蜗牛液体
Eww, snail trail. Yucky.
‎却令人感到异常舒缓
But oddly soothing.
‎早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‎早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‎早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‎早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‎早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‎早安 海绵宝宝！
Good morning, SpongeBob!
‎早安 派大星！
Good morning, Patrick!
‎你们这两个傻子别吵了！
Would you two knuckleheads keep it down out there?!
‎早安 章鱼哥！
Good morning, Squidward!
‎来吧 盖瑞！吃早餐！
Come on, Gary! Breakfast!
‎（盖瑞）
‎（海绵宝宝）
‎不用客气
You're welcome.
‎谁要抓痒痒？
Who wants a belly scratch?
‎我好爱你 盖瑞
I love you so much, Gary.
‎看看这是什么？
What's this?
‎我们等你把那个排出来吧
Okay, that'll come out later.
‎海绵宝宝：营救大冒险
‎我像是生活在超现实边缘
♪ Living like I'm on the edge Of surreality ♪
‎早安 海绵宝宝
Morning, SpongeBob.
‎但一切都会安好
♪ But I know everything is gonna be cool ♪
只要有你在
♪ As long as you're here with me ♪
‎我们会替彼此分忧
♪ We're gonna lighten up Each other's load ♪
‎一同面对前方的颠簸道路
♪ When bumps and curves Come on the road ♪
‎只要我们齐心协力
♪ 'Cause we are all in it together ♪
‎誓死不渝
♪ And that's forever ♪
‎比奇堡四季如夏
♪ It's always suer In Bikini Bottom ♪
‎（开麦之夜）
‎到了十二月份
♪ And in December ♪
‎我们仍唱着开心的歌谣
♪ We're singing la-di-da-da ♪
‎比奇堡四季如夏
♪ It's always suer in Bikini ♪
♪ In Bikini Bottom ♪
‎没有什么比这个更好了
♪ It doesn't get better than that ♪
‎钱！钱！钱！
Money! Money! Money!
‎糟糕！我要想早点的话 就快迟到了
Ooh! I'm late if I'm gonna be early.
‎别担心 盖瑞宝贝 在你还来不及说
Oh, don't worry, Gare-Bear. I'll be back before you can say,
‎“他为何残忍地抛下我？” ‎我就回来啦
"Why did he cruelly abandon me like that?"
‎新一天的开始也是令人头疼的一天
Another day, another migraine.
‎在那小子出现之前至少能有片刻安宁
At least I'll get a little peace and quiet before that little--
‎早安 章鱼哥！ ‎真是美好的早晨 对吧？
Good morning, Squidward! - And isn't it a lovely morning?
‎不 我不要跟你说话
Nope. Not talking to you.
‎我今天尤其没兴趣参与你的胡闹事
I'm especially not getting involved in any of your nonsense today.
‎每次吃亏的总是我
I always end up with the wrong end of the stick.
‎好吧 章鱼哥
Okay, Squidward.
‎你该知道 ‎老格特鲁德近来变得十分挑剔
But you should know that Old Gertrude's getting pretty finicky these days.
‎老格特鲁德？那是什么人？
Old Gertrude? Who the kelp is that?
‎你与她共事多年！
You've worked with her for years!
她是厨房里的烤架
She's the eight-burner grill in the kitchen.
‎真是没完没了
It never ends.
‎若要开火
Anyway, to fire her up,
就得先激起她的火花
you've got to spark her flints manually and then…
‎再轻轻扭动她的开关
jiggle her gas jets just a little.
‎接着说她最喜欢的故事
And then read her favorite story:
‎“能干的小干锅”
"The Little Griddle Who Could."
‎第二章
Chapter Two:
‎肉饼说：“但我们刚离开冰箱 ‎仍冷冰冰的”
"But we are fresh from the freezer," said the patties, and we're c-c-c-cold."
‎小干锅回答：“别担心 ‎我会让你们感到暖烘烘的”
"Don't worry, I'll get you nice and warm,"said the Little Griddle.
‎我刚刚说了 我没兴趣
What'd I just say? I am not interested.
‎别把我牵连在内！
Don't involve me!
‎你说什么 章鱼哥？章鱼哥？
What'd you say, Squidward? Squidward?
‎没关系的 章鱼哥 ‎反正我一直都会在
Okay, Squidward, doesn't matter. I'll always be here anyway.
‎真是不幸
Unfortunately.
‎别偷懒 章鱼先生！快干活！
Stop yer loafing, Mr. Squidward! There's work to be done around here!
‎所有蟹堡王成员注意！
Attention, Krusty crew!
‎集体集合！
All hands on deck, front and center!
‎是的 蟹堡王船长！
Aye-aye, Cap'n Krabs, sir!
‎谁要跟我再来趟赚钱的冒险？
Now, who's ready to set sail on another adventure of making me money?
‎-出发吧 船员！ ‎-是的 船长！
Get moving, sailor! -Sir, yes, sir!
‎升起彩色旗子！
Raise the colors!
‎举起主帆！
Hoist the mainsail!
‎（蟹堡王）
‎部署烟囱！
Deploy smokestacks!
‎（客满）
‎（开始营业）
‎哦 这般景象真是百看不腻
Oh, never gets old.
‎珍惜这有限的时光吧 蟹老板
Enjoy it while you can, Mr. Eugene Krabs.
‎（投入钱币）
‎搞什么？
What the…?
‎该死的机器！
Stupid machine!
‎我刚才在做些什么？哦 是的
Where was I? Oh, yeah.
‎我今晚将实施 ‎第3087号的邪恶计划
Tonight I launch Evil Plan Number 3,087
‎夺走蟹堡王肉饼的秘方！
and finally take possession of the Krabby Patty secret formula!
‎真是棒 又一个邪恶的计划
Great. Another evil plan.
‎又一个邪恶计划不好吗？
What's wrong with another evil plan?
‎没什么 只不过我们记录失败的墙 ‎快被填满了
Oh, nothing, it's just we're running out of room on the Wall of Failure.
‎记录失败的墙？
Wall of Fai--?
‎凯伦 你为何要收集这些？
Karen, why do you keep collecting these?
‎作为纪念
Heh. Memories.
‎今晚不同以往
H! Well, tonight… is gonna be different.
‎我的电脑妻子凯伦
You see, Karen, my computer wife,
‎每当我想偷走那个秘方时
every time I've tried to steal that formula,
‎蟹老板都试图阻扰我
Krabs has tried to thwart me.
‎不是蟹老板
not Mr. Krabs.
‎但今晚…你说什么？
But tonight, that all-- What?
‎阻扰你的不是蟹老板 亲爱的
It's not Mr. Krabs, sweetheart. I've checked the data.
‎我查过数据 问题人物是海绵宝宝
It's SpongeBob who's the problem.
‎你好
Hello.
‎哦 烦死了 跟那傻子有什么关联？
Oh, fish sticks. What could that boob have to do with it?
‎他其实一点也不傻
Boob savant, you mean.
‎一直以来搞乱你计划的是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob is the one who keeps foiling your plans,
‎-而非蟹老板 ‎-惊喜！
not Mr. Krabs.
‎别胡说八道了 凯伦 肯定是蟹老板
Oh, nonsense. It's Krabs, Karen, I know it is.
‎今晚 我终于能
And tonight, I will finally extract…
‎复仇！
my revenge!
‎你会迟回吗？
Will you be late?
‎像我这般天才 ‎是不被时间限制的 凯伦
You can't put a clock on genius, Karen.
‎上菜！快！
Order up! Move it, let's go!
‎是的 大厨！
Aye-aye, Chef!
‎请好好享用你点的蟹堡王肉饼！
One for you. Enjoy your Krabby Patty. Enjoy!
‎上菜！快啊 海绵宝宝！
Order up! Come on, SpongeBob!
‎-炸物大厨海绵宝宝驾到！ ‎-炸物大厨海绵宝宝驾到！
Coming, Fry Cook SpongeBob! -Coming, Fry Cook SpongeBob!
‎-你好啊 海绵宝宝！ ‎-嗨 珊迪！
Hiya, SpongeBob! Hi, Sandy!
‎你知道吗？将来一切都会变自动化
Did you know that in the future everything will be automated?
‎真的？肚子疼也会自动化吗？
Really? Even stomachaches? -
‎我要问蟹老板是否愿意
I'm gonna see if Mr. Krabs wants to be
‎成为我新科技的早期采用者
an early adopter of my new technology.
‎什么？
Wait, what?
你要用机器人来取代我？ ‎别这么做！
You're gonna replace me with a robot? Don't do it!
‎才不是 傻瓜 那种事迟早会发生的
No, silly, that's gonna happen anyway.
‎我说的是更具创新性的初创企业
This is something much more innovative and start-uppy.
‎我只给你六十秒
You have sixty seconds.
‎它的名字叫做奥托！
Its name is Otto!
‎我的名字叫奥托 能如何为您服务？
My name is Otto. How may I serve you?
‎这是一个全自动化的餐馆老板
It's an automated restaurant owner.
‎全自动化？
H Automated?
‎听起来价格昂贵 没兴趣
Sounds expensive. Not interested.
‎奥托无需领取薪酬
Otto doesn't require a salary.
‎它也能做出冷酷无情的抉择
And it can make cold, heartless decisions
‎像是解雇人 因为它没心没肺
like firing people, because it doesn't have a heart.
‎可不是
Ow. -You don't say.
‎-你被解雇了！ ‎-太棒了！
You're fired. -Amazing!
‎我爱钱 我好爱钱
I love money. I love money.
‎一台冰冷毫无感情的机械机器人
A cold, unfeeling mechanical robot
‎就像我自己冷冰冰无情的甲壳心
after me own cold, unfeeling crustacean heart.
‎我会接受并好好培育奥托
I'll take it and nurture it
‎待他如亲生儿子
and I will love Otto like he was me own son.
‎谢谢你 爸爸
Thank you, Daddy.
‎太好了！ ‎你绝不会后悔这个决定 蟹老板
Yippee! You're not gonna regret this, Mr. Krabs.
‎-你被解雇了 ‎-那真是百听不厌
You're fired. Oh, I could listen to that all day.
‎我是说真的
No, seriously.
你不是我们的合适人选
We decided to go in a different direction.
‎你被解雇了
You're fired.
‎什么？
What?
‎别逼我叫来保安
Don't make me call security.
‎-你被解雇了 ‎-你才被解雇了！
You're fired. -No, yer fired!
‎-不 你被解雇了 ‎-你被解雇了 你这讨人厌的机器！
No, you're fired. -Yer fired, ye infernal machine!
‎我没被解雇 你被解雇了
I'm not fired, you're fired.
‎（机械回收费：5美元）
‎虐待机器人
Robot abuse. Robot abuse.
‎你被解雇了
You're fired.
‎这是什么玩意？
What the heck is this thing?
‎不知道 但我要带回家 可爱极了
I don't know, but I'm taking it home.
‎什么？
It's so cute. -What?!
‎来吧 小机器人 我们去吃宵夜
Come on, little robot. Let's get you some supper.
‎-这一点也不好笑 凯伦 ‎-安静点 痞老板
Not even funny, Karen. -Quiet, Plankton.
‎-别听他说 ‎-凯伦！
Shh, Don't listen to him. -Karen!
‎我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom.
‎（已打烊）
‎海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
‎你离开前得确保这厨房 ‎被打扫干净 小子
Be sure this kitchen's in shipshape shape before ye head out, boy.
‎是 蟹老板先生
Oui, oui, Monsieur Boss Man Krabs.
‎有我办事 这厨房肯定一尘不染
Once I am done here, zees kitchen shall be completely spotless.
‎随你怎么说吧 对了！
Whatever.
‎我在六号桌找到这个 ‎未食用过的蟹堡王肉饼
I found this uneaten Krabby Patty on table six.
‎-你知道该怎么做
You know what to do with it.
‎-蟹老板！
Right away, Mr. K!
我会妥当处理掉
I'll see that it's disposed of properly.
‎谁说要处理掉？
Who said anything about disposing of?
‎我们明天再拿来卖
We'll sell it again tomorrow…
‎在我们的复古风遗赠手工餐点上推出
on our legacy artisanal vintage throwback menu.
‎晚安！
Good night!
‎我还是赶紧打扫吧
Oh! I better start cleaning.
‎我准备好了！
I'm ready!
‎（小心地面湿滑！）
‎晚安了 格特鲁德！
Well, good night, Gertrude!
‎晚安 炸锅 晚安 肉饼
Good night, fryer. Good night, patty.
‎晚安 腌黄瓜
Good night, pickles. Mwah!
‎晚安 海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob.
‎你好啊 蟹堡王肉饼！
Hello, Krabby Patty!
‎此刻
And now…
‎是动手的时机
Just got to get it.
‎太好了！
Yes!
‎（投入钱币）
‎等等 不要‎不要 不！
Wait, wait. No.No. No!
‎愚蠢的投币式…
Stupid coin-operated…
‎过来啊
Come here, come here…
‎大成功！
Bingo!
‎快到爸爸这里来
Come to Papa.
‎只需几分钟 ‎秘方就属于我！
In just a few minutes the formula will be mine!
‎（秘方分析中）
‎（分析完毕）
‎太好了！蟹老板的快餐帝国将失败
Yes! Krabs's fast-food empire will fail
‎比奇堡将由我统治
and I will rule Bikini Bottom,
‎成为新一任的废食国王！
as its new slop king!
‎我就知道会这样！
I knew it! -
‎秘方！
The formula!
‎我就知道钥匙留在这里 ‎我真是个傻瓜
I knew I left my keys in here. Oh, silly me.
‎快给我过来！
Come here, you!
‎没钥匙 真是奇怪 到哪去了？
No keys. That's weird. Where could they be?
‎好极了！不行
Yes! No.
‎钥匙 你在哪？
Keys, where are you?
‎快显示钥匙的位置吧！
Come on, show me keys! -
‎到手了！
Gotcha!
‎不 不要！
No. No!
‎好痛
Ow.
‎原来一直都在我裤袋里！
They were in my pocket the whole time!
‎问题人物是海绵宝宝
It's SpongeBob who's the problem.
‎我现在明白了
I get it.
‎（与此同时）
‎就在此时 在七海的统治者
Meanwhile, at the palace of King Poseidon…
‎波塞冬国王的宫殿里
…ruler of the Seven Seas.
‎（波塞冬宫殿 赌场）
‎大臣！
Chancellor!
Chancellor! -
‎大臣！
Chancellor!
‎怎么了 殿下？您召唤我？
Yo. What's up, sire? You sent for me?
‎大臣 看看我！
Chancellor, look. Look at me!
‎三千岁的皮肤状态
3,000 years old and check out my skin.
‎跟婴儿的屁股一样光滑
It's like a baby's butt.
‎您真是长生不老 青春常驻 殿下
Ageless, sire. Looking fresh.
‎这都归功于我的臣子们 对吧？
Ha! I owe it to my subjects to look fabulous, don't you think?
‎您还有其他义务在身 殿下
There are other obligations, sire.
‎像是统治国家之类的要事
Like ruling and stuff. Let's see…
‎我需要您在这些税项和法令
I need your signature on these taxes, decrees,
‎以及此宣战书和我的薪水单上签名
this here declaration of war and my paycheck.
‎-是吗？ ‎-是的
Is that right? -Yeah.
‎好吧
Very good.
‎天啊 大臣
Oh, Chancellor,
你何时才能学会 ‎专注于真正重要的事？
when will you learn to focus on what really matters?
‎君主政权与他自身的 ‎皮肤护理制度同样强大
A monarch's regime is only as powerful as his skin care regime.
‎我同意
Word. -hm.
‎有些人甚至说我长得像希腊神
You know, some say I have a face like a Greek god.
‎您确实是位希腊神
Well, you are a Greek god, so…
‎-等等
Whoa! Wait, is…
那是一条皱纹吗？ ‎-在哪？
Is that a wrinkle? -Where?
‎是的！是皱纹！
It is! It's a wrinkle!
‎我看上去像被遗忘在冰箱里 ‎干巴巴的老鳄梨！
I look like an old avocado that's been left and forgotten in the fridge!
‎又来了
Here it comes.
‎我好丑！
I'm ugly!
‎放到哪去了？
Oh, now, where is it?
‎那个有眼睛的圆壳爬行物
The crawly thing with the round shell and the eyes.
‎到底在哪？
Where is it?
‎在这里 殿下 您的皇家蜗牛
Here you go, sire. Your Royal Snail.
‎哦 谢谢你
Oh! Oh, oh, thank you.
‎这类软体动物的复兴能力 ‎犹如做过一千次的面部护理
This mollusk has the rejuvenating power of a thousand facials.
‎什么？怎么是空的？
What?! Is it empty?
‎快拿走！
Take it away!
立即给我送上 ‎另一只海蜗牛！
Bring me another sea snail at once!
‎大臣！
Chancellor! -Okay, uh…
‎我实话实说吧 已没有蜗牛了
Full disclosure, man, uh… We're out of snails.
‎什么？
What?!
‎实际上 整个蜗牛种群已被…
In fact, the entire snail population has been, uh…
‎该怎么说呢？已被耗尽了
What's the word? Oh, yeah… depleted.
‎-你的意思是没有蜗牛了？
You're telling me there are…no more snails?
‎-确实没有蜗牛了
There are no more snails.
‎-你确定？ ‎-我十分有把握
And you're confident of that? -Relatively confident.
‎大臣 为了赫耳墨斯
Oh, Chancellor, for the love of Hermes,
‎我愿意用我的王国换取一只蜗牛！
my kingdom for a snail!
‎不行 这么做太仓促了
No, no, no. I'm being hasty.
‎我愿意用半个王国换取一只蜗牛！
Half my kingdom for a snail!
‎不 这应当做为恩赐
No, no, no, a boon. Yes.
‎我将恩赐任何送我蜗牛的人
I'll grant a boon to whomever shall bring me a snail.
‎明白 我会起草法令 殿下
Gotcha. I'll draw up the decree, sire.
‎（皇家法令）
‎来自波塞冬国王的皇家法令？
A Royal Decree from King Poseidon?
‎“至所有海洋公民 ‎国王立即寻求一只蜗牛
"To all citizens of the sea, the King requires a snail at once…
‎什么皮肤保养之类的事”
blah blah blah skin care blah blah--"
‎等等
Wait a minute.
‎蜗牛？
A snail?
‎这太完美了
No, it's too perfect.
‎能够同时去除盖瑞和海绵宝宝
Get rid of Gary, get rid of SpongeBob.
‎太好了
Oh, yeah.
‎盖瑞 我到家了！
Gary, I'm home!
‎盖瑞宝贝？你在哪 朋友？
Gare-Bear? Hey, where are you, buddy?
‎盖瑞？
Gary?
‎你肯定在…不在
You must be in the-- No.
‎盖瑞？
Gary?
‎盖瑞？盖瑞！
Gary? Gary, Gary, Gary! Gary!
‎盖瑞！盖瑞去哪了？
Gary! Where's Gary?
‎盖瑞！
Gary!
‎（蜗牛走失 请联系海绵宝宝）
‎盖瑞 你在哪？
Gary, where are you?
‎哦 盖瑞
Oh, Gary.
‎自遇见你那天起 我就爱着你
I loved you since the first day we met.
‎（珊瑚夏令营）
‎你好啊 小蜗牛
Hello, little snail.
‎你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
‎是“盖瑞”吧？
"Gary", ?
‎你好 盖瑞
Well, hi, Gary.
‎你想交个朋友吗 盖瑞？
Gary, do you want to be friends?
‎我也是
Me, too.
‎海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob! SpongeBob!
‎海绵宝宝！我找到这张传单 ‎盖瑞走失了！
Hey, SpongeBob! I found this flyer. Gary's missing!
‎我知道 派大星
I know, Patrick.
‎海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‎派大星 盖瑞若出什么事的话
Oh, Patrick, if something were to happen to Gary, I, well…
‎我真不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do.
‎我为你感到难过 朋友
I'm sorry, buddy.
‎嘿！他或许有留下线索
Hey! Maybe he left a clue.
‎看！这是个线索！
Look! A clue!
‎盖瑞被绑架了！
Gary's been snailnapped!
‎并被带去失落的大西洋城！
And taken to The Lost City of Atlantic City!
‎真的吗？
Oh, really?
‎那太棒了！
That's awesome!
‎我们现在知道他在哪
Now we know where he is.
‎这一点也不棒 派大星 这里写着
Not really that awesome, Patrick. Listen to this.
‎“波塞冬称之为家的闻名浮华宫殿
"Made famous by the glitzy palace Poseidon calls home.
‎失落的大西洋城是个可怕
The Lost City of Atlantic City is a scary,
‎也道德沦陷的堕落之地”
vice-ridden cesspool of moral depravity."
‎哇 不会吧 那地方也被丢失了？
Wow. All that, and it's lost, too?
‎“波塞冬国王已证实 ‎自己是一个异想天开的暴君
"King Poseidon has proven himself a whimsical tyrant,
‎以斩首方式将臣子处死而闻名
known for executing his subjects by beheading them
‎并通过奢侈华丽的表演形态来展示
in a flamboyant floor show extravaganza.
‎我们对想来此地旅游的人 ‎提供的建议是
Our advice for those travelling here is…
‎不要来”
…don't."
‎这个波塞冬国王 ‎听起来像个很难搞的人
This King Poseidon sounds like a tough customer.
‎是的 很不好相处
Oh, yeah. Tough.
‎那又怎样？这关系到朋友
Aw, so what? This is about friends.
‎朋友是不会让彼此 ‎成为他人脸上的护肤品！
And friends don't let friends become somebody else's face cream!
‎朋友不会那么做
Not what friends do.
‎要是这趟旅途危险可怕呢？
So what if it's dangerous and scary?
‎那又怎样！
So what!
‎会有什么能阻止我前往那里救出盖瑞
What is stopping me right now from going there, rescuing Gary
‎并对抗这个波塞冬国王呢？
and standing up to this King Poseidon, ?
‎-我不知道！ ‎-我知道！
I don't know! -Well, I do!
‎-是什么？ ‎-我…
What is it? -I…
‎缺乏勇气
…don't have the courage.
‎哦 盖瑞
Oh, Gary.
‎搞什么！
Tartar sauce!
除了勇气 ‎还有什么最重要？
What's the next best thing to courage?
‎-解析能力？ ‎-不
Resolve? -No.
‎-坚忍不拔的毅力？ ‎-不是
Fortitude? -Nah.
‎-承诺？ ‎-也不对
Coitment? -Nope.
‎-必要的资金？英勇？ ‎-全都不对
Wherewithal? Bravery? -- No.
‎-勇猛不屈？坚毅？ ‎-什么？才不是
Valor. Grit? -What? No.
‎英雄主义？豪勇？有气魄？
Heroism? Gallantry? -Uh- Nah.
‎是哥们！一个帮手！
Moxie. -A buddy! A wingman!
‎一个帮手？
A wingman?
‎一个朋友
A friend.
‎真的吗 派大星？你要跟我一同去？
Really, Patrick? You'd go with me?
‎没错 我会跟在你身后！
Yeah… right behind you!
‎我嗅到的是公路之旅的味道吗？
Do I smell a road trip?
‎那可能是我的口气
That could be my breath.
‎好的
Okey-dokey.
‎我们来拟定计划 ‎派大星 你负责安排运输
Now, let's drill down on a plan. Pat, you're in charge of transpo.
‎切记 我不会开车 你也没有车子
Just remember, I don't drive and you don't have a car.
‎看路！
Beep, beep!
‎嘿 各位！
Hey, boys!
‎不知道你们是否用得着这老旧东西
Don't know if you have any use for this old thing,
‎像是用来进行任何旅行或救援任务
if you're going on any trips or journeys or quests or rescue missions.
‎若有需要的话 奥托能送你们上路
But if you are, Otto is your ticket.
‎奥托！
Otto!
‎你们只需告诉奥托要去哪就行了！
Just tell ol' Otto where you want to go and it will take you there!
‎请上车
All aboard.
‎-你被解雇了！ ‎-酷毙了！
You're fired. -Cool!
‎一艘自动驾驶的船
A self-driving boat.
‎谢谢你 痞老板 你最棒了！
Thanks, Plankton. You're the best!
‎可不是 再见了
I know, I know. Bye-bye.
‎-奥托 去找盖瑞 ‎-明白了
Otto. Find, Gary. -You got it.
‎不 派大星 你得说得更详细
No, Patrick. You got to be more specific.
‎奥托 去找蜗牛盖瑞
Otto, find Gary the snail.
‎重新计算中
Recalculating.
‎让我试试看吧
Ugh. Here, let me try.
‎把他们带去失落的大西洋城
Take them to The Lost City of Atlantic City
‎永不归来！
and don't ever come back!
‎用稍微夸张的语气往往能事半功倍
Never hurts to employ a little hyperbole.
‎能服务您是我的荣幸
It is my pleasure to serve you.
‎一路顺风 各位
Bon voyage, boys.
‎我准备好了 他们死定了
I'm ready. I'm ready. They're dead.
‎这就像哥们电影里的情节
This is gonna be like one of those buddy movies.
‎我们是好哥们！
We're the buddies!
‎-我不确定这是否相同 派大星
Not sure that really applies, Patrick, but...
‎为何不呢？
Why not?
‎我们是为共同目标出发的两个家伙
We're two dudes setting out with a coon goal.
‎我们在途中会为一点蠢事争吵而闹翻
We'll argue about something dumb, fight and break up…
‎最终却意识到
Only to come back together when we realize
‎我们不能没有彼此而复合
neither could do it without the other.
‎这简单而神奇
It's simple yet magical.
‎是的
Yeah.
‎我感觉这更像单一英雄的旅程
It feels more to me like the journey of a singular hero,
‎他排除万难 战胜逆境
who against all odds, triumphs over adversity.
‎我说是哥们电影
I say buddy movie
‎你非得说成愚蠢的事
and you say, oh, whatever that dumb thing was you just said.
‎愚蠢的事？你是说我很愚蠢？
Oh, really? Dumb thing?
‎派大星 你这人真是讽刺
I'm dumb? Oh, I love your sense of irony, Patrick.
‎谢谢你 我也喜欢这种 ‎“风驰”的感觉
Thank you. I love my sense of ironing, too.
‎要不是你脑子进水
Maybe if your head wasn't packed full of sand,
这还真是讽刺！
you could have ironing!
‎脑子进水也好过跟你一样
Well, better a head full of sand
‎脑袋死板板！
than a head full of rocks, like yours!
‎-够了！停车！
Ah! That's it! Stop the car!
‎-是的 快停车 奥托！
Yeah, stop the car, Otto!
‎（海牛兄弟律师行）
‎我很抱歉 派大星
Sorry, Patrick. Really.
‎我不该说你脑袋死板板
I shouldn't have said you have rocks in your head.
‎我也不该说你脑子进水
I shouldn't have said your brain was made of sand.
‎那样说实在恶毒也愚蠢
That was mean and dumb.
‎我们一笔勾销吧？
Okay. Let's just forget it, ?
‎这事从没发生过！
Never happened!
‎上车吧 各位
OTTO: Hop on in, guys.
‎我们又重新上路了
♪ On the road again ♪
‎来吧 各位
Come on, guys.
‎我迫不及待再次展开旅程
Ha, ha, ha!
‎不要
Nope.
‎跟朋友一同创作音乐 ‎才是我最爱的人生
♪ The life I love is making Music with my friends ♪
‎我迫不及待再次展开旅程
♪ And I can't wait to get On the road again ♪
‎蟹堡 耶！
Krabby! -One at a time, people.
‎一个一个来
One at a time.
‎章鱼哥 ‎厨房为何没端出蟹堡王肉饼？
Squidward, why ain't I seeing Krabby Patties rolling out the service window?
‎-海绵宝宝在哪？ ‎-我怎么知道？
Where's SpongeBob? -How should I know?
‎说实在 他不在更好
And, frankly, you won't find me complaining.
‎海绵宝宝！你搞什么？
SpongeBob! What's with yer lollygaggin' boy?
‎海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob? SpongeBob?
‎快给我出来！这是命令！
Get out here this instant! That's a direct order!
‎我搞不懂 他从未错过任何工作日
I don't get it. He has never missed a workday.
‎蟹堡王肉饼！
Krabby Patty! Krabby Patty!
‎嘿！我的蟹堡王肉饼呢？
Hey! Where are my Krabby Patties?
‎-我怎么知道？ ‎-就来了 先生！
How should I know? -It's coming, sir, it's coming!
‎章鱼哥 快进厨房做出蟹堡王肉饼
Squidward, get in that kitchen and whip up some Krabby Patties.
‎好的 格特鲁德 他那时怎么说的？
All right, Gertrude… Now, what did he say?
‎先激起她的火花
spark her flints.
‎再轻轻扭动她的开关 好的！
jiggle her jets. And… oh, yes!
‎“能干的小干锅”
"The Little Griddle Who Could."
‎肉饼说：“但我们刚离开冰箱 ‎仍冷冰冰的”
"We're fresh from the freezer," said the little--
‎-蟹老板 我们出了一点问题 ‎-章鱼哥！
Mr. Krabs, we've got a-- -Squidward!
‎快逃命！
Ow! Save… Ow! …yourself!
‎海绵宝宝若在的话 ‎就不会搞得一团乱了
We wouldn't be in this mess if SpongeBob was around.
‎海绵宝宝去哪了？
Where is SpongeBob?
‎我们在哪？
Where are we?
‎我们肯定是在做梦！
We must be dreaming!
‎你真有趣 海绵宝宝
You amuse me, SpongeBob.
‎两个人怎么能做同一个梦
Two people can't have the same dream,
‎更别说同时间做同一个梦
let alone be in that same dream at the same time.
‎这在哲学上站不住脚
That would be philosophically untenable.
‎确实 你提供了形而上学的难题
Indeed. You proffer a metaphysical conundrum.
‎等等 我们像聪明人一样对话
Wait, we're talking like smart people.
‎这肯定是一场梦！
This must be a dream!
‎再说 我们在地面上 还呼吸着空气
Plus, we're on the surface and we're…breathing air, so…
‎没错！
yeah! -
‎空气？
Air?!
‎嘿 前方有个小镇！
Hey, town up ahead!
‎“没希望峡谷” 这名字真有趣
"Goner Gulch." Ha! That's a funny name.
‎（地狱沙龙）
‎“地狱沙龙”
"The Inferno Saloon."
‎“踏入这里亦放弃所有希望”
"Ye who enter here abandon all hope."
‎我想这个意思其实是在说 ‎“不得借用厕所”
Guess that's another way of saying "no public restrooms".
‎有人吗？
Hello?
‎-奥托 留在附近 ‎-对 别开走
Otto, keep it close. -Yeah, don't go anywhere.
‎开走
Go anywhere.
‎能服务您是我的荣幸 你被解雇了
It is my pleasure to serve. You're fired.
‎我们现在该如何找到盖瑞？
Oh! How are we gonna find Gary now?
‎奥托或许只是去停车
Maybe Otto just went to park. -
‎你好
Hello.
‎你是谁？
Who are you?
‎我是一团风滚草 你可以叫我基哥
I am a simple tumbleweed. Call me Sage.
‎-风滚草基哥 ‎-嘿 风滚草基哥 这名字真不赖
Sage. -Hey, Sage. Good name.
‎谢谢 我用风滚草打造 ‎亦是风滚草基哥
Thanks. I'm made out of sage, and I am a sage.
‎这样十分妥当
So it works out pretty well.
‎我是派大星！
I'm Patrick!
在凯尔特语中的意思是 ‎“烤面包机”
My name means "toaster" in Celtic.
‎我很确定不是
Pretty sure it doesn't.
‎你们共享的梦隐藏着一个目的 ‎年轻的寻求者们
This dream you share has a hidden purpose, young seekers.
‎原来我们真的在做梦！
Oh! So we are in a dream!
‎而我就是织梦者 我的朋友
And I, friend, am the dream weaver.
‎哦 织梦者
♪ Ohh, dream weaver… ♪
‎哇 你进入到我们的脑里？
Whoa, are you inside our minds right now?
‎-是的 派大星 ‎-哇！
Yes, Patrick. -Wow!
‎我是来协助你这趟旅程 海绵宝宝
I am here to help you on your journey, SpongeBob.
‎但首先 你得接受一项挑战
But first, you must accept a challenge.
‎但我只想找出盖瑞并把他带回家
But, I just want to find Gary and bring him home.
‎-你爱盖瑞吗？ ‎-超过任何事！
Do you love Gary? -More than anything!
‎那么 年轻的海绵 ‎你一旦完成这项挑战
And, young sponge, once you meet this challenge
‎就能继续上路 找寻你宝贵的盖瑞
you may pass on to find your precious Gary.
‎-明白了 这说得通了 ‎-这就说得通了
Got it. Right. -Oh, right, that makes sense.
‎好恶心
Eww.
‎拿着这枚挑战币
Take this challenge coin.
‎-挑战币！ ‎-挑战币！
Challenge coin!
‎这会在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
It will give you courage when bravery is in short supply.
‎-哇！ ‎-酷毙了！
Whoa! -Cool!
‎你的挑战位于这道沙龙门后
Now, your challenge lies behind these saloon doors.
‎-我们走吧！ ‎-等一等
Let's go! Come on, Patrick. -Wait.
‎-我们去完成这项挑战 ‎-等等 各位！
Let's kill this challenge. -Wait, guys!
‎挑战币来了！
Challenge coin coming through!
‎我还没告诉你们挑战是什么！
I didn't give you your challenge!
‎耐心 风滚草基哥 你得有耐心
Patience, Sage. Patience.
‎好酷 是那种古老的钢琴手
Oh, cool. One of those old player pianos.
‎或是那种古老的钢琴手！
Or…one of those old piano players!
‎-好可怕的人！
Scary people!
‎确切地说 那是肉食的牛仔海盗僵尸
Flesh-eating cowboy pirate zombies, to be precise.
‎肉食的牛仔海盗僵尸？
Flesh-eating cowboy pirate zombies?!
‎这就是你们的挑战
This is your challenge.
‎将这些僵尸从尘世的束缚中解放出来 ‎并释放他们的灵魂
Free these zombies from their earthly binds and release their souls.
‎这若不是梦境 我早就吓坏了！
If this weren't a dream, I'd be freaking out right now!
‎对啊！
Oh, yeah!
‎我们在做梦
We are in a dream.
‎听好了 各位！
Okay, everyone!
‎我们是来释放你们被监禁的灵魂
We're here to release your imprisoned souls.
‎那是什么？
What was that?
‎邪恶的暗黑破坏神驾到
Ah, El Diablo the Wicked approaches.
‎暗黑破坏神
♪ El Diablo El Diablo ♪
‎他是个坏到骨子里的恶人
♪ Very bad man ♪
‎暗黑破坏神？
El Diablo?
‎他是这群僵尸的主人
Master of this zombie crew.
‎-糟糕 ‎-他听起来坏透了
Uh-oh. -He sounds bad.
‎祝你们好运
Good luck.
‎派大星 僵尸都向这里蜂拥而至！
Patrick, the zombies are swarming!
‎他们会吃掉我们的脑子！
They're gonna eat our brains! -
‎快跳舞！
♪ Dance! ♪
‎我是史努比老大 ‎台上台下都同一个风格
♪ Boss Dogg ♪ ♪ Even when I'm on I'm off, y'all ♪
‎挑战大王得付出代价
♪ Lookin' for the King It'll cost y'all ♪
‎你们赶紧走吧 是迷路了吧？
♪ You better leave now are you lost, dawg? ♪
‎僵尸之王 我听到他的脚步声
♪ The Zombie King Yeah, I hear him coming ♪
‎传奇的人物来势汹汹
♪ OG ghoul with a thirst For the run-in ♪
‎你们来错了地方 就等着送死吧
♪ You in the wrong bar Wrong town ♪ ♪ Got a spot to fill ♪
‎真正的胜者即将出现
♪ The real deal Coming down that hill ♪
‎啃着你们的脑子做早餐
♪ Your brains for breakfast ♪
‎灵魂当作小菜
♪ Soul on the menu Major checklist ♪
‎食尸鬼和地精 快守护出口吧
♪ Ghouls, goblins Guard the exit ♪
‎他眼中的怒火 不难发现
♪ The fire in his eyes Ain't hard to catch it ♪
‎邪恶的暗黑破坏神 我知道这很可怕
♪ El Diablo, the haunting Taunting veterano ♪ ♪ It's scary, I know ♪
‎没希望峡谷事故重重
♪ The Goner Gulch Where the drama is ♪
但别恨这游戏 ‎谁叫我们都陷入了僵尸行业
♪ But don't hate the game We in the zombie biz ♪
‎我们一同舞蹈时就能感受到爱意
♪We feel the love ♪ ♪ When we all dance together ♪
‎齐心协力
♪ Together ♪
‎我们共同成就了毕生的胜利
♪ We made it, made it Up all life long ♪
‎我们不会就此罢休
♪ We won't stop… ♪
‎暗黑破坏神驾到！
♪ El Diablo is here! ♪
‎快跳舞！我们是最邪恶的团队
♪Dance! ♪ ♪We the baddest crew ♪
‎把手高高举起！你还害怕什么？
♪Hands high! ♪ ♪What's eating you? ♪
‎我们来势汹汹！
♪Us! ♪ ♪We comin' through ♪
‎我们最擅长的就是杀戮！
♪ Killing it is how we do! ♪
‎暗黑破坏神驾到 ‎嗅一嗅那腐烂的气味
♪ El Diablo's on his way Smell the odor of decay ♪
‎尽情舞动吧 ‎因为我们最擅长的就是杀戮！
♪ Dance, we came to slay ♪ ♪ 'Cause killing it Is how we do! ♪
‎我说过我不在的时候不准跳舞！
What did I tell you about dancing when I'm not here?!
‎老大 今天是自由式星期五！
But, boss, it's Freestyle Friday!
‎好的 是我搞错了
Oh. Okay, my bad.
‎嘿 海绵宝宝？
Hey. Yo, SpongeBob?
‎我得走了 这里交给你
I got to dip. Y'all got this.
‎把囚犯带到我办公室
Bring the prisoners to my office.
‎那家伙指的囚犯是什么意思？
What'd that guy mean by prisoners?
‎你们竟敢踏入该死的鬼城
So, you dare to enter the ghost town of the damned,
‎还闯进我的恶魔巢穴
barge into my demon's lair…
‎告诉我的僵尸们
telling my zombies…
‎你将释放他们的灵魂
that you're gonna free their souls…
‎好像这一切都不算什么！
like it ain't no thing!
‎暗黑破坏神先生 ‎好在我们都在梦境中
Well, Mr. Diablo, the good thing is we're in a dream.
‎-这是个共同的梦 ‎-是的 我们共享的梦境中
A shared dream. -Right, a shared dream.
‎你实在无需动怒
So there's no need to get all bent out of shape about it.
‎-这一切都不是真实的！ ‎-因为这只是个梦境
It's not real! -'Cause it's a dream.
‎是谁告诉你的？那疯狂的灌木家伙？
Who told you that? That crazy bush guy?
‎或许吧
Uh… aybe.
‎他应该告诉你们的是 ‎这才不是什么梦境！
What he should've told you was it's not a dream!
‎他或许说得对 派大星 ‎一切感觉好真实
He might be right, Patrick. That felt pretty real.
‎是的 真的好痛
Yeah, that really hurt.
‎快逃！
Run!
‎等一等 派大星
Hang on, Patrick.
‎邪恶的恶魔 快消失！
Foul demon, be gone!
‎那是什么玩意？
What the heck is that?
‎我看起来像是停车收费表吗？
What do I look like, a parking meter?
‎但风滚草基哥说过…
But Sage said--
‎投币式洗衣机就在大街上
Coin laundry's right down the street.
‎真是可悲！
That's pathetic!
‎快远离那些窗帘！
Get away from those curtains!
‎-什么？这些窗帘吗？ ‎-这些窗帘真不赖
What? These curtains? -Oh, these are nice curtains.
‎没错 摸起来软绵绵的
Oh, they are. So soft.
‎真是怪异
That's weird.
‎这些窗帘好像发出怪声
These curtains are making a strange sound.
‎我想是窗帘杆需要抹油了
I think the curtain rod needs some oil.
‎窗帘杆一旦坏掉
Once the rod goes,
‎你还不如换一套全新的窗帘
you're probably better off getting a whole new set of curtains.
‎暗黑破坏神先生 ‎你是否有其他的窗帘…
Oh, Mr. Diablo, do you have any other cur--
‎派大星 我们赶紧逃离这里吧！
Patrick, I think we should get out of here!
‎嘿 各位！
Hey, everybody!
‎暗黑破坏神先生说谁都别去打扰他
El Diablo says he doesn't want to be disturbed.
‎是的 他心情有些焦灼
Yeah, he's feeling a little burnt…
‎好像被烤焦一样 ‎-再见了！
out. -Toodle-oo!
‎-拜拜！ ‎-不用送了！
Buh-bye! -See you!
‎保重了！
Take care!
‎谢谢你 海绵宝宝
Thank ye, SpongeBob.
‎我们终于自由了！
We're finally free!
‎再见了 伙伴们！
Adiós, mateys!
‎-我们终于自由了
Thanks, SpongeBob. -We're finally free.
‎-祝你们旅途顺利 二位
Good luck on your journey, boys.
‎你知道这意味着什么吗？
Do you know what this means?
‎我们通过这项挑战了！
We passed the challenge!
‎我们现在能去找盖瑞了！
Now we can find Gary! Yay!
‎暗黑破坏神
♪ El Diablo El Diablo ♪
‎（暗黑破坏神办公室）
‎奥托！
Otto!
‎你们好啊 伙伴们
Howdy, partners.
‎等等！不能忘了“勇气”
Wait! Can't forget the "courage."
‎是他！
It's him! -Yikes!
奥托 快离开这里！
Come on, Otto. Let's go!
‎奥托 快啊！
Come on, come on, Otto!
‎奥托 开快点！
Step on it, Otto! Go! Go! -Faster! Go faster!
‎奥托 快！
Go, Otto, go!
‎他是个坏到骨子里的恶人
♪ Very bad man ♪
‎-醒醒吧 你们的梦被解雇了 ‎-奥托！
Faster! Wake up. Your dream is fired.
‎再快
Faster -? Oh!
‎太好了！我们又回到海底了
Phew! We're back on the bottom.
‎看吧 派大星？那肯定是一场梦
See, Patrick? It must have been a dream.
‎那更像是一场幻境
More of a vision really.
‎-风滚草基哥？ ‎-你好啊 风滚草基哥
Sage? -Oh. Hi, Sage.
‎-你们好 ‎-原来你是真实的
Hello. -You are real.
‎如你所愿 才能看到你看不到的东西
As real as your desire to see that which you cannot.
‎我看不到的东西是盖瑞
Yeah, well, that which I cannot see is Gary.
‎我得知道发生了什么事
I got to know what's happening.
‎我将实现你的这个愿望
This wish I grant you.
‎通过神秘的第四维空间
Through the mystical fabric of the fourth dimension,
‎你能在事情正发生的同时
you may now view what's happening
‎查看发生了什么事
at the same time as things are happening to you.
‎与此同时之窗
Behold. The Window of Meanwhile.
‎与此同时之窗！
The Window of Meanwhile!
‎这有什么用途？
What's it do?
‎这就像并行动作中的视频点播服务
It's like the Video On Demand service of parallel action.
‎看一看吧
Have a look.
‎嘿 派大星 别挡着
Whoa… Hey, Patrick. Down in front.
‎看 派大星 他在那里！
Look, Patrick, there he is!
‎他看起来没事
Yeah, he looks all right.
嘿 盖瑞！
Hey, Gary!
‎-他看上去没那么糟糕
He doesn't look so bad.
‎-他看起来挺舒适的！
He looks pretty comfy!
‎-看来我们无需惊慌 ‎-没错！
No reason to panic. -Yeah!
‎-他看上去有被好好照顾 ‎-看我找到了什么
He looks like he's well taken care of.
‎蜗牛时间到
Look what I found. Snail time.
‎你好啊 宝贝
Hello, precious. -
‎盖瑞？
Gary?
‎希望你不会用尽汁水 ‎否则下场就跟其他的一样
I hope you don't run out of juice, or you'll end up like the others.
‎什么？
What?!
‎好极了
Oh, yes.
‎-盖瑞！你听得到吗？ ‎-盖瑞！
Gary! Gary, hello? -Gary!
‎与此同时之窗不是这样操作的
Okay, the Window of Meanwhile doesn't really work that way.
‎-盖瑞！快逃离那里！ ‎-盖瑞！
Gary, run! Get out of there! -Gary!
‎这不是视频聊天应用程序
It's not a video chat app like Skype or FaceTime, or anything.
‎-我们得赶紧去那里！盖瑞！ ‎-这里！盖瑞！
We got to hurry! Gary! -Over here! Gary!
他完全听不到你说的
Totally can't hear you.
‎你好啊 我的老朋友 蟹老板！
Hello, Eugene, old friend!
‎生意如何？
How's business?
‎很糟糕吗？好极了
Bad? Good.
‎餐饮业就是这般残酷 ‎不是大丰收就是闹饥荒
Well, that's restaurants for you, ? Feast or famine.
‎我离题了
But I digress.
‎你不如当个有气度的败者 ‎乖乖把秘方交出来吧？
Why don't you be a good little loser and hand over the secret formula?
‎拿去吧
Take it. It's yours.
‎全都拿走吧
Take it all.
‎等等
Wait…
‎你放弃了？
You're giving up?
‎痞老板 我不奢望你能感同身受
Oh, Plankton… I wouldn't expect you to understand.
‎但不知何故 少了海绵宝宝
But somehow, without SpongeBob,
‎这里的一切
this whole thing…
‎都变得毫无意义！
just doesn't make sense anymore!
‎你不能这样
You can't do that.
‎我耗上毕生的事业就为这一刻
I've spent my entire career waiting for this moment
‎你却像只泄气的鲸鱼一蹶不振？
and you roll over like a harpooned whale?
‎我不会让你如此夺走我的复仇大计！
I won't let you rob me of my vengeance!
‎代我问候你美丽的妻子
Give my regards to your lovely wife.
‎这感觉
This doesn't, uh…
‎没有想象中雀跃
feel quite as good as, uh…
‎太好了 我赢了
Yay, I won.
‎恭喜 您已抵达目的地
Congratulations. You have arrived at your destination.
‎失落的大西洋城！
The Lost City of Atlantic City!
‎好漂亮
It's pretty.
‎当心 年轻的寻求者们
Beware, young seekers.
‎眼前的一切都是扭曲的
All is distortion.
‎你们一不小心就会被失落之城 ‎诱导到她善变的拥抱中
If you aren't careful, The Lost City will draw you into her fickle embrace,
‎她会用眼花缭乱的景象干扰你
blind you with her dazzling distractions
‎诱惑你参与她各式各样的机遇游戏
and tempt you with her fleeting games of chance.
‎你们无论做什么
Whatever you do,
‎都不要被误入歧途
don't be led astray,
别失去专注力
don't lose focus
‎更别忘了你们来此的目的
and don't forget why you came here.
‎-忘记？才怪 ‎-谢了 风滚草基哥
Don't forget. Good one. -Thanks, Sage-meister.
‎我们懂得该怎么做
I think we got this. -Yeah, Sage.
‎是的 风滚草基哥 ‎你一路来都很有智慧
I mean, you've been pretty good up until now, but,
‎但别忘了 我爱盖瑞超过全世界！
I love Gary more than anything in the whole world!
‎-我们来此的目的是把他带走
And we came here to get him back.
‎-好的
Okay.
‎我才不担心我们会失去专注力
I wouldn't worry about us losing any focus.
‎天啊
Oh, boy.
‎我们得专注 宝贝
We got focus to burn, baby--
‎-棉花糖！ ‎-冰淇淋！
Cotton candy! -Ice cream!
‎吉拿棒！
Churros!
‎你们好啊！
What's up?
‎（赌场）
‎好酷 这里可以用真钱 ‎换取这些
Isn't it cool how they let you trade in your real money
圆形小塑胶
for these little plastic circles?
‎我好爱钱！
I love money!
‎赌场都有股魔幻的魅力
Casinos are magical.
‎-你不介意我把这个放下吧 先生？
Would you mind if I put this down, sir?
‎-你爱放哪就放哪
Place it wherever you like.
‎放在L的位置上
Just put it on L.
‎-派大星 那不是字母L 是数字7
Patrick, that's not an L, that's a seven.
‎-数字7跟字母L一样？好奇怪
Seven starts with an L? That's weird.
‎七号！
Seven!
‎更多的圆形小塑胶！
More plastic circles!
‎-你们是谁？ ‎-我们是你们的随行人员
Who are you guys? -We're your entourage.
‎请下注
Place your bets.
‎来吧 七号！
Come on, seven!
‎幸运的七号！大赢家！
Lucky seven! Winner!
‎真是疯狂的人生！
♪ Living la vida loca! ♪
‎七号！七号！七号！
Seven! Seven! Seven!
‎七号 七号 七号
Seven. Seven. Seven.
‎-嘿 派大星！ ‎-什么事 海绵宝贝？
Hey, Patrick! -What's up, Spongey-Dawg?
‎-我把钱都输光了 ‎-我也是！
I lost all my money. -Me, too!
‎（就在今夜！唱片骑士派大星）
‎狂欢的人儿！
Party people!
‎大家都到哪去了？
Oh. Where is everybody?
‎我感觉自己像是吞下了一个海胆
I feel like I swallowed a sea urchin.
‎我也是
Me, too.
‎嘿 我真的吞下海胆！
Hey, I did swallow a sea urchin!
‎看吧
Well, well, well.
‎风滚草基哥老大！ ‎见到你真好 朋友！
Sagester! Good to see ya, pal!
‎做得真是好 各位
Nice work, boys.
‎你们把我的金玉良言全都抛在脑后
Way to take my pearls of wisdom and flush them down the toilet.
‎糟糕 等等 我们是否…
Oh, no. Wait, did we…?
‎没提高警惕并完全失去专注力？
Lose focus like I told you not to?
‎专注力？
Focus?
‎让我重整你们的思绪
Let me jangle your minds.
‎你们来此是为夺回失去的东西
You came here to get back something you lost.
‎我…
Uh… Hm.
‎一样你非常爱的东西
Something you love.
‎-盖瑞！ ‎-盖瑞！
Gary!
‎是的 盖瑞
Yeah, Gary.
‎说实在 被困在风滚草已经够难受了
Seriously, it's hard enough being stuck in a tumbleweed…
‎派大星 我们得去找盖瑞！
Patrick, we got to find Gary!
‎但应对你们让我想把自己点燃
…but dealing with you two makes me want to light myself on fire.
‎风滚草基哥朋友
Sage, buddy.
‎我们能否再看与此同时之窗
Can we please look into the Window of Meanwhile
‎找出盖瑞在哪？
one more time to see where Gary is?
‎不 这不是随选服务
No, it's not an on-demand service.
‎尤其不适合在自己呕吐物中 ‎昏睡一整夜的人
And especially not for people who pass out and sleep in their own vomit all night.
‎那不是呕吐物 是口水
It's not vomit. It's drool.
‎你们很幸运能在这里醒来
Fortunately for you, you woke up right here.
‎这里是波塞冬宫殿的门口
On the steps of Poseidon's Palace.
‎-哇 ‎-哇
Whoa. -Wow.
‎振作起来 快去！
Now get it together. Go!
‎好的 盖瑞 我们来救你了！
All right, Gary. We're coming for ya!
‎我的天啊
Boy, oh, boy. Hey…
‎就快了 盖瑞
Almost there, Gary.
‎嘿 上车吧！
Hey, hop on!
‎是商店免费赠送的
They're just giving these things away at the grocery store.
‎好主意 朋友
Good call, buddy.
‎帅哥借过！
Hot stuff coming through!
‎看看这地方 派大星
Get a load of this place, Patrick.
‎你好
Hello.
‎我们求见波塞冬国王殿下
We would like an audience with His Majesty King Poseidon.
‎没问题 有两位俗人要见波塞冬 ‎让我查查看 你们想得美
Oh, sure. Let me check. Two rubes to see Poseidon. No.
‎（倒车）
‎-嘿 兄弟 我们是蓝鳍组合
Hey, dude. We're the Blue Fin Group.
‎-好的 这里请
Of course. Right this--
‎（贵宾专用通道）
‎蓝鳍组合！不！
The Blue Fin Group! No!
‎（舞台入口）
‎我是蒂芙尼哈多克 我只是来玩乐的
I'm Tiffany Haddock and I'm here just for the halibut.
‎好的
All right then.
我们下一组表演者…
Our next performers are gonna knock--
‎（水色房）
‎波塞冬？
Poseidon?
‎我们见到国王了
We are getting an audience with the King.
‎来吧 请开始表演！
Well, let's have it. Perform, please!
‎嘿 阿卡哇卡玛卡米亚是只河豚鱼
♪ Hey! Aka Waka Maka Mia ♪ ♪Was a puffer fish ♪
‎想变得大过河豚鱼 是他唯一的愿望
♪ Being bigger than a puffer Was his only wish ♪
‎他于是大口喘气大口呼气 ‎圆滚滚的膨胀
♪ And so he huffed, he puffed ♪ ♪ He billowed and he blew ♪
‎盖瑞！
Gary!
‎盖瑞 我来了 朋友！
Gary, I'm coming, buddy!
‎抱歉 请让开！
Excuse me. Sorry. My bad. Whoop.
‎抱歉
Sorry. Whoa!
‎不好意思 波塞冬国王殿下
Hi, there! Excuse me, King Poseidon, sire.
‎你对盖瑞有些误解
There's been a misunderstanding about Gary.
‎盖瑞？
Gary? -
‎-盖瑞 ‎-盖瑞？
Gary. -Gary?
‎你正用来涂抹脸的那只蜗牛
The snail that you're rubbing all over your face right now.
‎胡说八道 再说 ‎这只蜗牛的名字叫弗雷德
Nonsense. Besides, this snail's name is Fred.
‎“弗雷德”？你替盖瑞改名？
"Fred?" You renamed Gary?
‎-弗雷德 ‎-盖瑞
Fred. -Gary.
‎-弗雷德！ ‎-盖瑞！
Fred! Fred! -Gary! Gary!
Fred! -Gary!
‎弗雷德！
Fred!
‎捉住他们！
Seize them!
‎盖瑞！
Gary!
‎但盖瑞爱我！我也爱他！
But Gary loves me! And I love him.
‎呀呼！
Yeehaw!
‎前进！
Incoming!
‎火箭乖乖
Good rockets.
‎海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‎准备出发了 小子
Get yer co-pilot goggles, dude,
我们去骑火箭
'cause we're goin' sleddin'!
‎海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‎你在吗？
You in here?
‎海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
‎海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
‎这真奇怪
That's weird.
‎这里有古怪
Something's fishy around here.
‎快说 你们对海绵宝宝做了什么？
All right, what'd y'all do with SpongeBob?
‎我们不知道他去了哪 珊迪
We don't know where he is, Sandy.
‎他已经很多天没来过了
Hasn't been here in days.
‎少跟我耍花样 头足类动物
Don't you play coy with me, cephalopod.
‎还有你这个节肢动物！从实招来
And you, arthropod! Start talking.
‎他在哪？
Where is he?
被捆绑在地下室？ ‎还是被塞进你的后备箱？
Tied up in the basement? Stuffed in your trunk?
‎我是不可能会伤害那小子的
Nay, I could never harm the lad.
‎他的缺席教会我很多事
His absence has taught me that much.
‎我指的不只是被亏损的钱财 ‎他的离去让我难以适应
And I'm not just talking about the money I'm losing with him gone.
‎好吧 有一半原因是因为亏损钱
Okay, fifty percent talking about the money
‎另一半是因为我真的想念那小子
and fifty percent talking about I truly miss the boy.
‎我很不愿承认 ‎但少了他一切都不同了
I hate to admit it, but things just aren't the same without him.
‎不可否认 我们都需要海绵宝宝
There's no denying it. We need SpongeBob.
‎你们没想过他此刻 ‎或许需要我们的帮忙？
Did anyone ever stop to think that he might need us?
‎我是鲈鱼珀金斯 ‎在失落的大西洋城为您报导
This is Perch Perkins coming to you from The Lost City of Atlantic City.
‎我此刻位于波塞冬宫殿
I'm standing on the strip outside
‎和赌场外的地皮上
Poseidon's Palace and Casino,
‎今晚有两名嫌疑犯因刑事拘留被带走
where two suspects have been taken into custody tonight…
‎他们企图夺走皇家蜗牛
…following an attempt on the Royal Snail.
‎这两名嫌犯 ‎海绵和海星冒充舞台演出
The sponge and sea star were impersonating a lounge act
‎企图夺走波塞冬最宝贵的软体动物
when they made an attempt on Poseidon's prize mollusk.
‎那是盖瑞！
It's Gary!
‎嫌疑人的车在高速追逐后被拘押
The suspects' vehicle was apprehended after a high-speed chase.
‎蟹老板 奥托在哪？
Mr. Krabs. What happened to Otto?
‎他自动休假！
Well, he took an automated vacation!
‎在相关报导中 ‎波塞冬宫殿下令御前演出
In a related story, Poseidon's Palace presents a coand performance,
‎周五晚在水色房处决嫌犯
featuring the execution of the suspects in the Aqua Room this Friday night.
‎处决嫌犯？鱼身保护令法则呢？
Execution of the suspects? What happened to habeas swordfish?
‎这将是充满欢乐的家庭活动 ‎由凯尔皮G做开场演出
It's a fun-filled family event, with opening act Kelpy G.
‎只限一场演出 门票仍在出售中
One performance only, tickets still available.
‎-我们得去救他们！ ‎-立即启程
We've got to go help them! -We embark iediately.
‎不好意思
Excuse me.
‎我能跟着去吗？
Can I tag along?
‎痞老板？这事跟你有什么关联？
Plankton? What have you got to do with this?
‎我…
I… I…
‎我或许有那么一丁点的责任
I might have had a teensy-weensy hand in a very--
‎好的 我们上车再说
Yeah, yeah, we'll hear about it in the car.
‎章鱼哥先生 你也一同去吗？
Mr. Squidward, are ya coming?
‎哈！你想得美
Ha! Fat chance.
‎休想要我错过任何一场 ‎凯尔皮G的演出 算我一份
Fat chance I'd miss a Kelpy G performance. I'm in.
‎前往蟹堡王肉饼汽车！
To the Pattymobile!
‎什么？我们得开这台老爷车？
What, this old tub?
‎别用外表来衡量 ‎蟹堡王肉饼汽车 章鱼哥
Never judge a Pattymobile by its bun, Squidward.
‎我们出发吧！
Let's light this puppy!
‎（点火）
‎呀呼！
Yeehaw!
‎我的妈呀！
Moy!
‎海绵宝宝？
? SpongeBob?
‎你没事吧？
Are you okay?
‎朋友 我对此感到抱歉
Hey, buddy. Sorry about this.
‎这不是你的错 派大星
It's not your fault, Patrick.
‎你一直都是最真诚的朋友
You've been a true friend this whole time.
‎你对我的友谊永不动摇 只不过…
Never wavered, never faltered. It's just…
‎我失败了！
I failed, that's all!
‎我再也看不见无辜的小盖瑞了
And I'll never see innocent little Gary again.
‎哦 我的心碎了！
Oh, my heart is broken!
‎别这样
Oh, come on now.
‎振作起来 一切还未结束 海绵宝宝
Buck up. It's not over yet, SpongeBob.
‎我感觉这早已成定局了 这糟透了
It sure feels over. And crappy.
‎别忘了每个钱币都有正反两面
Just saying there's two sides to every coin.
‎派大星 这关钱币什么事…
Oh, Patrick, what does a coin have to--
‎等等 你刚刚说的是钱币？
Wait, did you just say "coin"?
‎我吗？好像不是吧
Me? don't think so.
‎你确实有提到钱币！
You did. You said "coin"!
‎我不太记得了
Not remembering that exactly. -
‎喂？
Hello?
‎挑战币！没错！
The challenge coin! Of course!
‎你还不明白吗 派大星？ ‎我们获救了！
Oh, don't you see, Patrick? We're saved!
‎我接电话了
I said hello.
‎派大星 不见了！
Patrick, it's gone!
‎那又怎样？那枚挑战币很重要吗？
Meh. Was the challenge coin really that useful?
‎喂？
Hello?
‎真是的！愚蠢的恶作剧来电者
Oh! Stupid prank callers.
‎嘿 等一等
Hey, wait a sec.
‎我把那交给你保管 还记得吗？
I gave it to you, remember? For safe keeping.
‎不记得
No.
‎拜托 那不过是昨晚的事！ ‎我们当时在玩掷骰子
Come on, it was last night! We were at the crappie tables.
‎赢家！快下注吧
Winner! Place your bets.
‎拜托 七号！七号！
Come on, seven! Come on, seven! Come on, seven!
‎是你！
You!
‎你把我的挑战币输掉了！
You gambled away my challenge coin!
‎你因为一个愚蠢的赌注 ‎毁掉我们整个任务！
You wrecked our entire mission with one stupid bet!
‎那还不是因为你一直对我说
Well, only after you kept saying…
‎快下注 派大星！快下注！
Let it ride, Patrick! Let it ride!
‎但是 海绵宝宝
Whoo! -But, SpongeBob…
‎要是你明天需要用挑战币‎来召唤勇气呢？
What if you need the challenge coin tomorrow to help you suon your courage?
‎明天是留给弱者的！
Tomorrow is for weenies!
‎明天已来临 看看谁才是弱者
Well, it's tomorrow and guess who's the weenie.
‎我真是
I… can't…
‎无法相信你！
believe you!
‎你无法相信我？开什么玩笑？
You can't believe me? Are you serious right now?
‎你或许可以相信即将发生的
Well! Maybe you can believe this.
‎因为我走了！
I'm out of here!
‎别再回来！
And don't come back!
‎别担心 我不会的！
Oh, don't worry, I won't!
‎-好极了！ ‎-永不回头！
Good! -Ever!
‎-好啊！ ‎-好棒！
Fine! -Super!
‎嘿 你们这两个失败者
Hey, losers.
‎你好啊 风滚草基哥
Oh, hey, Sage.
‎风滚草基哥 你来得正好
Sage, glad you're here.
‎猜猜是谁把我的挑战币输掉
Guess who gambled away my challenge coin.
‎猜猜是谁把自己的问题都怪罪于他人
Guess who blames everyone else for his troubles.
‎够了！
Enough!
‎我有说过你们是我担任精神向导
Did I mention you are the worst epic heroes
‎最糟糕的史诗英雄吗？
for whom I have ever been a spirit guide?
‎-我们今早好像有谈到
Um, I think we went over that this morning.
‎-好像是的
I believe we did, yeah.
‎海绵宝宝 那枚钱币只是一个象征
SpongeBob, the coin was just a symbol.
‎你所寻的英勇来自你内心
The courage you seek is inside you,
‎而非那枚钱币
not in the coin.
‎这会在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
And it will come to you in your hour of need.
‎此刻不正是我英勇不足之时？
But isn't this my hour of need?
‎哦 不是的 情况会变得更糟
Oh, no. It gets way worse.
‎再见了！
Bye!
‎-更糟？ ‎-那家伙说还会更糟糕
Worse? -Dude said way worse.
‎准备好囚犯
Prepare the prisoners.
‎他指的应该不是我们吧
Oh, that couldn't be for us.
‎让你们受苦的时刻到了 ‎不 是让你们受表扬的时刻
It's your big moment to fry… I mean, shine.
‎那是冲着我们来的 派大星！ ‎我们死定了！
It is for us, Patrick! We're gonna die!
‎我就是这样把海绵宝宝引出比奇堡的
And that's how I got SpongeBob out of Bikini Bottom.
‎-你真是邪恶！ ‎-等等 这听起来真不错
Why, that's monstrous! -Wait, that sounds good.
‎哦 该死的
Oh, brother.
‎不然你以为会如何？我这人就是邪恶
What do you expect? I'm evil.
‎我们专注于救人计划吧
Let's just focus on the plan.
‎我们即将抵达失落的大西洋城
We're approaching The Lost City of Atlantic City.
‎让一让！
Make way there, make way! -
‎“海绵与海星的华丽死刑”？
"Sponge and Star Execution Extravaganza"?
‎没时间了！
No time to lose!
‎女士先生们 欢迎来到水色房
Ladies and gentlefish, welcome to the Aqua Room, y'all.
‎海底下最盛大的演出
The greatest show underwater.
‎我的拥护者们
My groupies and groupers…
‎-我们爱你 蒂芙尼！ ‎-来点欢呼声吧！
We love you, Tiffany! -Yeah holler at your girl!
‎各位准备好被娱乐了吗？
Are you ready to be entertained?
‎我听不见 你准备好被娱乐了吗？
I can't hear you. Are you ready to be entertained?
‎好的 让我们见见参赛者
All right, then, let's meet the contestants.
‎在这个角落的是海绵和海星
In this corner, a sponge and a star…
‎（被告）
‎海洋中最臭名昭著的两名罪犯！
…two of the ocean's most notorious criminals!
‎（喝倒彩）
‎在这一角落是国王殿下的代表
And in this corner, representing His Majesty the King,
‎波塞冬国王的大臣！
Poseidon's very own Chancellor!
‎（鼓掌）
‎响起鼓声吧 音乐大师
Now drum roll, maestro.
‎大家一同欢迎残酷无情 ‎挥舞斧子的疯子
Put your fins together for the duke of the dirty deed,
‎执行过无数次死刑的伯爵
the earl of execution, that axe-wielding maniac…
‎雷默特！
…oh, yeah, Lemont!
‎哦 我好爱雷默特 他好有力量
Oh, I love me some Lemont. He's so strong.
‎（死刑台）
‎女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
‎让我们用爵士乐的瞬间
with a moment of smooth jazz
‎来纪念即将完蛋的人
in memory of the soon-to-be-goners,
‎有请凯尔皮G
I give you Kelpy G.
‎派大星 我感到很愧疚
Oh, Patrick, I feel terrible.
‎这一切都是我连累你的
I dragged you into this whole mess.
‎没关系 海绵宝宝
It's okay, SpongeBob.
‎我已对控方提出了抗辩！
I made a plea deal with the prosecution!
‎那就好…等等 你做了什么？
Oh, that's good-- Wait, you did what?
‎我只需要做的是…
All I have to do is, uh… oh, yeah!
‎“向被告提出有罪证供”
"Bring incriminating evidence against the defendant."
‎派大星 我就是被告
Patrick, I'm the defendant.
‎是你吗？
You are? Oh.
‎开始审判！
Let the proceedings begin!
‎法官阁下 我想呈上证据
Your Honor, I would like to enter into evidence
‎海蜗牛一只 ‎他的名字是弗雷德
one sea snail. Name: Fred.
‎盖瑞！
Gary!
‎我对你只想说一句岂有此理！
How dare you! That's about all I can say.
‎你竟敢闯入这里
How dare you come here
‎到我们尊贵君主的庇护所
to the sanctuary of our revered sovereign,
‎意图夺走他的命脉
to rob him of his very lifeblood,
‎他的绝世美貌
his adorable good looks.
‎继续说下去
Go on.
‎你真是好大的胆子
How indeed dare you.
‎有罪！
Guilty!
‎雷默特！雷默特！雷默特！
Lemont! Lemont! Lemont!
‎等等！
Hold it!
‎庭上
If it please the court,
请允许我为海绵宝宝做出辩解
I'd like to say something in SpongeBob's defense.
‎不被庭上允许
It does not please the court.
‎请坐下 头戴鱼缸的松鼠
Sit down, squirrel with fishbowl on head.
‎但是 法官阁下 ‎有辩解才能让演出更为精彩
But, sire, a strong defense makes for a better show.
‎你们说对吗 观众们？
Isn't that right, audience?
‎好吧 我允许
All right, all right! I'll allow it.
‎谢谢你 法官阁下
Thank you, Your Honor.
‎女士先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
海绵宝宝一直 ‎都在我身边支持鼓励我
SpongeBob has always been there for me.
‎这得一路回溯到那个夏令营
Even going all the way back to suer camp.
‎我们也是在那时相识的
In fact, that's where we all met.
‎我…
I'm…
‎准备好了！
ready!
‎（珊瑚夏令营）
‎看看这些酷毙的活动！
Look at all the cool activities!
‎露营和划独木舟
Camping. Canoeing.
‎骑行海马！
Seahorse-back riding!
‎拔河比赛和观赏鲸鱼
Tug-of-war. Whale watching.
‎别看了行吗？
Do you mind?
‎杂耍比赛和收缩足球赛！
Juggling contests. Shrink-wrap soccer!
‎还有更多更多
And more.
‎（更多更多）
‎嘿 你们这些海洋生物！让开！
Hey, y'all critters of the sea! Look out below!
‎我是来自德克萨斯州的珊迪
I'm Sandy Cheeks from Texas.
‎嗨 珊迪 我是海绵宝宝
Hi, Sandy. I'm SpongeBob.
‎很高兴认识你
Pleased to meet ya.
‎在德克萨斯州 ‎每个人都穿宇航服吗？
Does everybody wear spacesuits in Texas?
‎若想探访你们 ‎这些海洋生物时就得穿上
They do if they want to visit you underwater critters.
‎我们都在海面上呼吸空气
We all breathe air on the surface.
‎这是我们合成氧气的方式
It's just our way of synthesizing oxygen.
‎就犹如你们在水底一样
Same as you do with water.
‎哇 你是科学家吗？
Whoa. Are you a scientist?
‎才不是 我是一只松鼠
Naw, I'm just a squirrel.
‎我当不成科学家
I can't be a scientist.
‎即便那算是我的梦想
Even though it's kind of my dream.
‎珊迪 你快收回这句话！
Sandy Cheeks, you take that back!
‎只要是你想做的一定办得到！
I bet you can do anything.
‎真的吗？哇
Really? Wow.
‎我也能成为科学家？
Me a scientist?
‎科学
Science.
‎你真有趣 小家伙
You're a hoot, little dude.
‎我也很想生活在水底
I'd be just as likely to live down here
‎在有一棵树的玻璃圆顶里
in a glass dome with a tree in it.
‎凡事无绝对！
Ha-ha! -You never know!
‎他是第一个告诉我
He's the one that told me,
‎不论我是谁 出身如何
no matter who I was or where I came from,
‎我都该追逐我的梦想
I should follow my dream.
‎这就是一个真正的朋友 各位
That's a friend, people.
‎这也是为何在我眼里
And that's why, in my eyes…
‎海绵宝宝不可能是罪犯
SpongeBob is no criminal.
‎他是踏入海底最美好的小家伙
He's the best little fella to ever walk the sea bottom. And that's…
‎这就是我的感受
That's just how I feel about it. So…
‎恳请大家不要伤害他
Please, don't hurt him.
‎这家伙触犯了法律！
This man broke the law!
‎那法律为
The law of: "You should stay home
‎“你该乖乖留在家中 ‎接受有人偷走你蜗牛的事实”
and accept the fact that somebody stole your snail."
‎那法律为
The law of:
‎“我或许什么也做不了”
"There's probably nothing I can do about it."
‎但根据这只海星的观点
Well, in this sea star's opinion,
‎这些法律都应该被触犯 ‎而海绵宝宝也证实了这一点！
those laws should be broken and SpongeBob is proof of it!
‎他唯一犯下的罪行
All he's guilty of
‎就是有毅力试图营救一个朋友
is having the fortitude to try and rescue a friend.
‎我又怎么会知道呢？
How do I know?
‎我与他初次相识时 ‎不过是木头上一个孤独的物体
Oh, I was just a lonely bump on a log when I first met him.
‎嗨 我的名字是…
Hi, my name-- -
Hi, my name--
‎你好啊 我叫海绵宝宝 ‎你叫什么名字？
Hello my name is SpongeBob, what's your name?
‎我叫派派派大星
I'm Pa-Pa-Patrick.
‎你为何哭泣 派派派大星？
Why are you crying, Pa-Pa-Patrick?
‎我好想家
I'm homesick.
‎那确实是个充分的理由
Well, that's a pretty good reason.
‎或许你需要的是一个朋友
Maybe all you need is a friend. -
‎我没有任何朋友！
I don't have any friends!
‎-你现在有朋友了 ‎-真的？
Well, you've got one now. -Really?
‎-那是谁？ ‎-是我！
Who is it? -It's me!
‎-你是认真的？ ‎-当然 走吧！
Do you mean it? -Of course. Come on!
‎这个贴心的小海绵
That sweet little sponge
‎拯救了这个可悲的小海星
rescued this miserable little sea star.
‎自那天起 我们的友谊一如往昔 ‎法官阁下
And things haven't changed that much today, Your Honor.
‎我说的全都发自内心 朋友
My heart, buddy.
‎我不喜欢海绵宝宝
I don't like SpongeBob.
‎事实上 我十分憎恨他
In fact, I revile him.
‎我也是在夏令营认识这个傻子
Anyway, I, too, met this nabob in suer camp.
‎那记忆清晰如昨天
I remember it like it was yesterday.
‎那是我的重大夜晚
It was my big night.
‎珊瑚营的年度才艺秀
The Annual Camp Coral Talent Show.
‎一等奖是令人垂涎的坎比奖
And first prize was the coveted Campy Award.
‎谢谢你 莱瑞
Thank you, Larry.
大家别忘了投票
Remember, people, don't forget to vote.
‎对我来说 那座奖杯是属于我的
As far as I was concerned, the trophy was as good as mine.
‎嘿 章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward-- -Bup, bup, bup, bup.
‎别吵 我在预备赛事
Quiet. I'm in pregame right now.
‎我得赢得奖项
I've got an award to win.
‎阿卡哇卡玛卡米亚是只河豚鱼
♪ Aka Waka Maka Mia Was a puffer fish ♪
‎奖项是属于我的
The Campy is mine.
‎我把天籁般的单簧管演奏呈现给观众
I bathed the audience with the sounds of my heavenly clarinet playing.
‎谢谢你 章鱼哥 那真是美妙
Thank you, Squidward. Just lovely.
‎谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
‎奖项属于…
And the Campy goes to…
‎给我吧
I'll take that.
‎海绵宝宝和派大星
SpongeBob and Patrick!
‎不！
No! No! No!
‎这是不可能的！我的妈呀！
This isn't happening! No! Moy!
‎我被夺走属于我的东西
I was robbed.
‎我从此再也不弹奏单簧管了
And never to play the clarinet again.
‎-章鱼哥！ ‎-走开！
Squidward! -Go away!
‎我和派大星
Patrick and I were, um,
跟其中一位辅导员聊天 ‎接下来肯定会让你意想不到
talking to one of the counselors and guess what?
‎他们搞错了 坎比奖其实该归你！
There was a big mistake and you actually won the Campy Award!
‎没错
That's right. Yup.
‎-我吗？ ‎-你的选票占压倒性多数
I… I did? -In a landslide.
‎他们会算错票数还真是怪异
So weird they would've miscounted like that.
‎但也不是没可能
But I guess it's possible
‎-做得好 章鱼哥 ‎-你比谁都实至名归
Nice work, Squidward. -No one deserves it more.
‎哇
Wow.
‎你也一定要继续弹奏这个
And don't ever stop playing this.
‎我的单簧管
My clarinet.
‎我真的做到了！
Look at me. I really did it!
‎太好了！
Yay!
‎这也是为何 我虽然讨厌海绵宝宝
Which is why, even though I can't stand SpongeBob…
‎但在同时
but at the same time, well…
‎我也爱他
I love him.
‎我对他爱恨难分
I love him and I hate him.
‎他就像加了盐巴的雪糕
He's like ice cream with salt on it,
‎因为他贴心却也很烦人
because he's sweet and super annoying.
‎他的人很好
He's nice and
‎却也令人受不了的讨厌！
nails-on-chalkboard annoying!
‎好吧 他大部分时候都非常讨人厌
Okay, fine, he's mostly super freaking annoying.
‎但这叽喳的讨厌鬼
But, this little nattering noodge…
‎是我的朋友
is my friend.
‎他罪不该死
And he doesn't deserve to die.
‎若庭上允许的话
I'll be saying my piece now, if it be pleasing the court.
我将开始我的说辞
I suppose I could stand up here
‎我可以告诉各位 ‎海绵宝宝是如何改变我的人生
and tell you how SpongeBob changed me life.
‎但我不会对大家倾诉
But, I won't.
‎我或许也能分享他对我的启发
I might even speak about how he inspired me
‎我当时是一个潦倒的餐饮车摊贩
when I was just a small-time vendor with a broken-down luncheonette.
‎但我也不想多说
But I won't.
‎该死的 我甚至能说说看
Heck, I'd probably mention how he encouraged me
‎他如何鼓励我开自己的餐馆
to start up me own restaurant.
‎你有一天应该自己开餐馆
You should open up your own restaurant, someday.
‎售卖蟹堡王肉饼闻名的蟹堡王！
The Krusty Krab, made famous by me delicious Krabby Patties!
‎顺道一提 周三有买一送一活动 ‎请把这个传下去
Two-for-one Wednesdays, by the way. Pass these around.
‎（蟹堡王 打九折）
‎但我也不会说 我才不要赞美他
But, I won't. Nay, you'll hear none such praise from me.
‎因为这不足以显示他的美好
Because it wouldn't do him full justice.
‎这小子的善良远远超出这一切
It wouldn't begin to describe the size of the lad's heart.
‎他的心很大很大
Which is huge.
‎他也将其投入所有事 像他的烹饪…
And he puts that heart into everything he does.
‎-上菜！ ‎-打扫
The cooking… -Order up! cleaning…
‎以及烹煮美味可口的蟹堡王肉饼
…serving up the delicious Krabby Patties.
‎但有趣的是
But that's the funny thing.
‎我曾以为我的蟹堡王肉饼秘方
I used to think me secret Krabby Patty formula
‎是让我迈向成功的原因
was also the secret to me success.
‎还有 我们从11点供应早餐 ‎周末12点起
We serve breakfast till 11, by the way, 12 on weekends.
‎海绵宝宝来替我工作之后
It wasn't until SpongeBob came to work for me
‎我才意识到 原来秘方
that I realized the formula
‎不只是材料成分表和烹煮方式
is more than just a list of ingredients and flavor-capturing methods.
‎那已远远超出一个被私心霸占的食谱
It's more than a jealously guarded recipe.
‎真正的秘方
The real secret formula
‎就坐在那里
is sitting right here.
‎那就是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants.
‎做好准备
Get ready.
‎音乐大师？
Ahem! Maestro?
‎一个秘方就犹如一个食谱
♪ A formula is something Like a recipe ♪
‎一个食谱就犹如一个计划
♪ A recipe is something Like a plan ♪
‎带有元素和测量
♪ With elements and measurements ♪
‎全由一双稳固的手灌入
♪ All mixed together by a steady hand ♪
‎但你得当心 否则肯定会伤心
♪ But careful you must be Or you'll be sad you see ♪
‎若在其中缺少了灵魂
♪ If somehow in the mix It has no soul ♪
‎能让这美好酱汁
♪ So what's the one ingredient ♪
升华的唯一材料 ‎究竟是什么？
♪ That turns this awesome sauce To liquid gold? ♪
‎让我来告诉你吧！
I'll tell ya!
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula Is you, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‎在我茶里的蜜糖其实就是你
♪ The honey in my tea, you know Is you, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‎滚烫的泡沫
♪The bubbles in the boil ♪ -
‎缺一不可的香精油
♪ The one essential oil It's true ♪
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula Is you, you ♪
‎海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob!
‎就是你
♪You, you ♪
‎在辽阔的海底世界
♪ What in the wide watery world ♪
‎若少了你会是如何？
♪ Would it be like without you? ♪
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula Is you, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‎在我茶里的蜜糖其实就是你
♪ The honey in my tea, you know Is you, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‎滚烫的泡沫
♪ The bubbles in the boil ♪
‎缺一不可的香精油
♪ The one essential oil It's true ♪
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula Is you, you ♪
‎海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob! ♪You, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ The secret to the formula ♪
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪Is you, you ♪
‎真是精彩万分！
So entertaining!
‎秘方的秘密其实就是你
♪ The secret to the formula Is you, you ♪
‎就是你
♪ You, you ♪
‎真有趣！
Ha! Hilarious!
‎我的蜗牛！
My snail!
‎停止！这是个把戏！快捉住他们！
Halt! It's a trick! Seize them!
‎盖瑞 你又回到我身边了
Gary, you're with me now.
‎我再也不会让任何人把你带走
I'll never let anyone take you again.
‎快！
Faster!
‎哇
Wow.
‎-派大星 你在做什么？
Yah! Patrick, what are you doing?
‎-免费的食物！
Free food!
‎捉住他！
Get him!
‎快来这里！
Come on, come on. In here!
‎站住！
Stop right there!
‎快进去！
Inside! Quick!
‎快啊！
Come on!
‎糟糕
Uh-oh.
‎快用力推 痞老板！
Push! Push, Plankton!
‎开什么玩笑？
You got to be kidding me!
‎逮到你了！
Peekaboo!
‎进攻！
Attack!
‎快进攻！
Attack! -
‎大家当心左侧！
Whoa! Watch your left flank, people!
‎击剑！还击！
Thrust! Now parry!
‎转圈 再转过来 竖趾旋转
Now pirouette. Turn around. Pivot!
‎用力拉 快！往右边！
Pull harder. Faster! To the right!
‎我们是否该选择留在章鱼哥那里？
Do you think we should've stayed in there with Squidward?
‎没事 他行的
Nah, he's got it.
‎大家去哪了？
Where is everybody?!
‎进攻！
Charge!
‎-章鱼哥！ ‎-章鱼哥！
Squidward!
‎章鱼哥！这里！
Squidward! Fall this way!
‎不 这里！
No, this way!
‎有人员倒下了
Man down.
‎接得好
Good catch.
‎-嘿 他们在那里！ ‎-快捉住他们！
Hey, there they are! -Get them!
‎嘿 你们好啊？
Yo, what's up?
‎奥托！
Otto!
‎我沉迷于赌博
I have a gambling problem.
‎奥托！
Otto!
‎有谁能借钱给我？
Could anyone lend me some money?
‎开往比奇堡！加速！
To Bikini Bottom! And step on it!
‎正在加速中
Stepping on it.
‎你们全都被解雇了
You're all fired.
‎前往代客泊车服务处！
To the valet!
‎这么快就走了吗 孩子们？
Leaving so soon, kids?
‎撑着 盖瑞 我会抓紧你的
Hang on, Gary. I won't let you go.
‎你们可真没礼貌 对吧？
Tsk, tsk. Rather impolite, don't you think?
‎这全都是他们的主意 殿下
It was all their idea, sire.
‎我…
And I…
‎爱死了！
…loved it!
‎等等 你没生我们的气？
Wait, so you're not mad at us?
‎没有 我已经好久没享受过
No! It's been a while since I've enjoyed
‎如此精彩的表演
such toe-tapping entertainment.
‎-一切都被赦免了！
All is forgiven!
取消所有控诉 ‎-太好了！
And all charges are dropped. -Hooray!
‎但有一个条件
On one condition.
‎海绵宝宝将归还我的蜗牛
SpongeBob will return my snail to me
‎别再耍花样了
without any more shilly-shally.
‎等等 什么？
Wait, what?
‎只要把蜗牛交出 你们全都能离开
Just hand over the snail and you can all go free.
‎但是我…
But… I… I…
‎海绵宝宝
SpongeBob.
‎风滚草基哥？是你吗？
Sage? Is that you?
‎你好啊
Hello.
‎风滚草基哥！嗨！
Sage! Hi!
‎切记
Remember…
‎你所寻的英勇来自你内心
The courage you seek is inside you.
‎在你英勇不足时 给予你勇气
And it will come to you in your hour of need.
‎勇气源自我内心
The courage is inside me.
‎勇气源自我内心！
The courage is inside me!
‎波塞冬先生 不行
Mr. Poseidon, no.
‎很抱歉 但我不会这么做
I'm sorry, but I won't do it.
‎什么？
What?
‎我太爱盖瑞 他也爱我
I love Gary too much, and he loves me.
‎我们若没有彼此都会很难过
If we didn't have each other, we'd be so sad. Well…
‎无论你对我们做些什么都无所谓
It wouldn't really matter what you'd do to us.
‎今天多谢我这些很棒的朋友们
And look. Today, thanks to these amazing friends,
‎我内心感到前所未有过的澎湃
my heart feels twice as big a s it ever did.
‎尤其是他们为我铤而走险
Especially after what they risked for me:
‎藐视法律并对抗强大的海洋之王
Flouting the law and defying the mighty king of the sea.
‎对抗？不是吧？
Defying? Really?
‎那当然不算是对抗国王
I wouldn't say defying the king.
‎在你臣子面前羞辱你
Humiliating you in front of your subjects.
‎-继续说下去 ‎-那更像是钦佩您的美德
Do go on. -More like admiring.
‎我完全赞同！
And totally agreeing with!
‎我只是来看凯尔皮G的演出
I just came to see Kelpy G.
‎他们全都为了我
And they did it all for me.
‎你若有像他们这样的朋友 ‎肯定能理解
I'm sure you'd understand if you had friends like these.
‎像他们这样的朋友？你在说些什么？
Friends like these? Wait, what?
‎像他们这样的朋友？
Friends like these?
‎我当然有像他们这样的朋友 ‎我交友满天下！
Of course I have friends like these. I have all kinds of friends!
‎我有好哥们也有死党
I have buddies, I have besties.
‎有好朋友也有普通朋友
I have home-slices, palsy-walsies.
‎我的友谊无限！
It's infinite!
‎大臣！快计算出我朋友的数据
Chancellor! Give us an exact number. The friend count, if you will.
‎好的 根据您最新的民调数据
okay, according to your latest polling data,
‎我们应该先获得更多的民调数据
we should get more polling data.
‎把那个给我
What? Give me that.
‎（喜欢指数：0 ‎讨厌指数：100）
‎我的粉丝们呢？
What about my adoring fans?
‎-没有 ‎-我的精英宫殿卫队呢？
Nope. -My elite palace guards?
‎我的私人教练呢？
What about my personal trainer?
‎-我的治疗师？ ‎-全都没有
My therapist? -Nada.
‎-我的纹身师傅？ ‎-还是没有
My tattoo artist? -Uh…nope.
‎-我的纹身去除师傅？ ‎-什么也没有
My tattoo removal artist? -No dice.
‎你身为我忠心耿耿的大臣 ‎肯定有吧？
B-But surely you, my chancellor, my loyal faithful…?
‎抱歉
Sorry.
‎阿波罗 带我走吧
Apollo, take me now.
‎我没有任何朋友！
I don't have any friends!
‎你现在有一个朋友了！
Well, you got one now!
‎真的？是谁？
Really? Who is it?
‎是我！我来做你的朋友吧！
It's me! I'll be your friend.
‎你是说真的？
Do you mean it?
‎是的 但朋友不会绑架 ‎朋友的宠物蜗牛
Yes. But friends don't kidnap friends' pet snails.
‎但我很需要那只蜗牛
But I need that snail.
‎看这里 我有一道很恶心的皱纹
Look, I have a horrible, disgusting wrinkle.
‎该死的 这跟马里亚纳海沟一样深！
Jumping jellyfish, it's the size of the Mariana Trench!
‎我开玩笑的
Kidding!
样貌根本不重要
Looks don't matter.
‎我们才不在乎细小的不完美 ‎甚至是大缺陷！
We don't care about little imperfections. Or even big ones!
‎-你看看章鱼哥就明白了 ‎-你这是什么意思？
Just look at Squidward. -What's that supposed to mean?
‎重要的是你内在的美好
What's important is what's inside.
‎你肯定能成为所有海洋生物
And I'm sure you can be a fair and kind king
‎公正善良的国王
to all the creatures of the sea.
‎你行的 殿下
I know you've got it in you, sir.
‎你只需抛开三千烦恼丝
If you'd just let your hair down a little.
‎什么？我的头发吗？等等
? My hair? Wait a minute.
‎你是说我不需要 ‎这头乌黑亮丽的秀发？
Are you suggesting that I don't need this gorgeous mane of wavy locks?
‎我也不需要这个颈夹？
That I don't require this neck clip?
‎也不需要完美洁白的牙齿！
Be gone, perfect shiny teeth!
‎这感觉太解放了！
This is so freeing!
‎也不要这胸板和腰带
To heck with this chest plate and girdle.
‎哇
Oh, wow. -
‎-太极端了？ ‎-不！一点也不会！
Too far? No! Not at all!
‎你看上去棒极了！
No, you look great!
‎谢谢你！这真是振奋人心
Oh, thank you! I find this so exhilarating.
‎也很符合我的年龄
So… age appropriate.
‎海绵宝宝 没几个人有勇气
SpongeBob, few possess the courage
‎对抗一个强大的国王
to stand up to a powerful king.
‎而你是少数中的佼佼者 我向你致敬
You, sir, are among those few. I salute you.
‎你做得好极了 海绵宝宝
Nailed it, SpongeBob.
‎风滚草基哥告退了
Sage out.
‎你留下盖瑞吧
You may keep Gary.
‎我祝福你们能共度许多开心的时光
And I wish you many happy years together.
‎谢谢！你听到了吗 盖瑞宝贝？
Thank you! Did you hear that, Gare-Bear?
‎请穿上皇袍 殿下 这里很冷
your royal robe, Your Highness.It's getting cold out here.
‎胡说八道 大臣 ‎我此刻已彻底解放天性！
Nonsense, Chancellor. I'm free!
‎您绝对是的
Ooh, you certainly are.
‎释放所有蜗牛！
And free the snails!
‎你说什么？
What's that?
‎把它们全都带回家？
All of them?
‎我到家了！
I'm home!
‎你好啊 盖瑞
Hello, Gary.
‎你好啊 布莱恩
Hello, Brian.
‎你好啊 珍娜 还有琼和露比
Hello, Janet. Hello, June. Hola, Lupe.
‎-早安 萨利！ ‎-嗨 布雷特！
Morning, Sally! -Hi, Brett!
‎（领养蜗牛）
‎来吧 盖瑞！你行的！
Come on, Gary! You can do it!
‎好极了！
Yeah!
‎（若有蜗牛走失 请联系派大星）
‎法比欧！你在哪 朋友？
Fabio! Where are you, buddy?
‎快来这里 法比欧！
Here, Fabio, Fabio, Fabio!
‎来吧 菲菲 不
Come on, Fifi. No.
‎（蟹堡王）
‎上菜！
Order up!
‎（比奇堡）
‎（蜗牛避难所）
‎（缅怀斯蒂芬海伦伯格）
‎字幕翻译：宋氏